

Vijayan Kuniyil Financial Controller- Hospitality Section

Tel: +9715 07729658

e mail: vijayamk@gmail.com,

Abu Dhabi, UAE

Presently on Visit Visa up to 10 Jun 22

Professional Summary

Focused Finance management professional with a proven track record earned through an industry career spanning 25 years of working for some of the most prominent hospitality organizations in U. A E.

Dedicated and enthusiastic Financial Controller for hotels and catering management companies in UAE and assisted in preopening and mobilization of hotels and large number of catering operations in reputed companies.

Strength

24 Years' Experience as Financial Controller in the field of Hospitality Accounting.(Hotels, Catering & corporate office of hospitality firm in U.A.E) & 5 Years as Accountant in Hospitality Field

Professional Experience

- Finance Manager Abu Dhabi Country Club
 Abu Dhabi Country Club owned by Abu Dhabi Sports Council From 20 Dec 2018 –
 20 Nov 2020
- **2.** Cluster Financial Controller
 Al Marfa Pearl Hotels Management LLC , Abu Dhabi

Financial Controller for three Hotels (Maisan Hotel Dubai, Mirfa Hotel & Liwa Hotel Abu Dhabi) .Did the Preopening of Maisan Hotel (256 Rooms) in D I P Dubai under the same Management From February 2014 till 15 Dec 2018.

3. Financial Controller

National Corporation for Tourism & Hotels (NCT&H) 4 years June 2009 - December 2013

Financial Controller in corporate office for the Catering & Support Service Division Green Mubazaraah Chalets (200 Deluxe Chalets complex in Al Ain) Al Ain Rest Houses (190 rooms)

4. Financial Controller

Nojoum Hospitality – Dubai (Hospitality Division of Al Ghurair Group)

1 year August 2008 - June 2009

Financial Controller from the preopening period. Deluxe Hotel apartment with (160 Rooms) & F & B outlets- Did the Pre Opening of this Property.

5. Financial Controller

National Corporation for Tourism & Hotels (NCT&H) 4 years March 2004 – July 2008

F.C in corporate office for the Catering & Support Service Division of NCT&H, Green Mubazaraah Chalets (200 Deluxe Chalets complex in Al Ain)& Al Ain Rest Houses (190 rooms)

6. Financial Controller

Mafraq Hotel Abu Dhabi - 4 star deluxe hotel ,managed by National Corporation for Tourism & Hotels (NCT&H) 6 years November 1998 - March 2004

Work Handled on the above assignments

Providing Strategic Financial Leadership and support to the property and its constituents' units.

Overseeing and directing the day to day financial operation of the division.

Budgeting, forecasting and analysing the financial data to support key financial decisions.

Cost analysis of existing operations and for potential new facilities

Monitoring and reporting of financial obligations and Reviews and recommendations for efficiency improvements

Finalisation of accounts on monthly basis.

Comparison of statement of affairs with the budget and forecast.

Preparation of yearly budget, revenue projection, forecast etc

To ensure efficient systems are in place to accurately record revenue and expenditure

- information that need to present on a regular basis.

Liaison with vendors, bankers, investors and insurance bodies for better relationship.

Reliever to the General Manager during his vacations and absence.

Special Task on above assignments

Did the preopening of Maisan Hotel in Dubai Investment Park from 2017 under the management of Al Marfa Pearl Hotels Management.

Did the pre opening of Nojoum Al Dar Hotel Apartments – 160 Rooms Deluxe Apartments with F & B Outlets in Dubai.

Did the pre opening of Green Mubazaraah Chalets Al Ain, a 200 Chalets Complex in Al Ain.

Mobilization of lot of Catering & support service centres in NCT&H

Did the ERP Solution Set up – Oracle Net Suite –Set up in Abu Dhabi Country Club

Computer Knowledge

Experienced in Opera

FBM Hotel package

Micros Point of Sale

Oracle Net Suite ERP

SAGE ACCPAC Financial Package

Paytrax Payroll package

Educational Qualification

M.Com Studied and passed from Department of Management Studies –

from the Campus of University of Calicut, Kerala, India - 1991

Specialisation in Financial Management

B.Com Passed with class from University of Calicut, kerala, India -

1988

Specialisation in Advanced Accounting, Cost Accounting and

Business Statistics

References

Mr. V. M Abraham

Director of Finance

GHQ- Officers Club Abu Dhabi

Tel: 050- 5743414

Abraham58sunny@gmail.com

Mr. Salim Touma

General Manager

Al Marfa Pearl Hotels Management, Abu Dhabi

Salim.touma@maisanhotel.ae

Mr. Shyam Saroff

Internal Audit Manager
National Corporation for Tourism & Hotels
ssaraf@ncth.ae

Tel: 050 4410660

Other Personal Information

Nationality Indian

Contact Number +97150- 7729658

E Mail vijayamk@gmail.com

Known Languages English, Hindi, Arabic (moderate), Malayalam

Date of Birth 21 April 1965

Marital Status Married
Sex Male

Status of Visa Visit Visa up to 10 Jun 22

Driving License UAE Driving License